## WEB APPLICATION DEVELOPER

Professional Summary

Web Application Developer with 5 years of experience in creating, maintaining and implementing source code that made up applications back-end functionalities and also in designing and developing user interfaces, testing, debugging, and t Proven ability in optimizing web functionality that improve data retrieval and workflow efficiencies.

Certifications

- Microsoft Certified Professional (MCP)
- microsoft certified technology specialist in C#

## Skills

- Expert in Java, PHP and C#
- J2EE architecture specialist
- Database design
- Excellent problem-solving abilities
- Windows and Linux
- CISCO router management
- Technical specifications creation
- Excellent diagnostic skills
- JavaSript Object-Oriented
- Angular JS
- Bootstrapp
- Website maintenance
- W3C DOM methods

Work History

Web Application Developer , 04/2014 to Current Siemens Corporation  $\hat{a} \in \text{``Seattle'}$  , WA

- Creating, maintaining and implementing source code for applications modules.
- Designed and developed user-friendly website, to improve user bug report.
- Trained over 20 staff members in internal web functions, including steps on how to independently make minor updates or changes.
- Fixed bugs from existing websites and implemented enhancements that significantly improved web functionality and speed Project management task by planning task with agile method, using Icescrum for setting up sprints.
- Taking part of meetings in order to elaborate a road map for application that includes evolutions, maintenance and giving support to over staff members.
- Established compatibility with third party software products by developing program for modification and integration.

Java Web Applications developer, 08/2013 to 04/2014 General Dynamics – Pittsburgh, PA

- Developed and implemented complex Internet and Intranet applications on multiple platforms.
- Provided continued maintenance and development of bug fixes and patch sets for existing web applications.
- Coordinated with systems partners to finalize designs and confirm requirements.
- Provided documentation on start-up, shut down and first level troubleshooting of processes to help desk staff.

Web Applications developer , 07/2011 to 06/2013 Serv2me – City , STATE

- Established compatibility with third party software products by developing program for modification and integration.
- Deploying and monitoring productions servers including handling load balancing.
- Developed dynamic and interactive websites for web agency customers.
- Developed and implemented complex Internet and Intranet applications on multiple platforms.
- Coordinated with systems partners to finalize designs and confirm requirements.
- Provided continued maintenance and development of bug fixes and patch sets for existing web applications.

## Education

Master of Science : Software Architecture , Current Conservatoire National des Arts et Métiers - City Software Architecture

Paris, FRANCEWeb application engineer: Fitec - City Bachelor of Science: University of Limoges - City